Critical Connections Between Measurements and Statistics
Welcome back to this session on the power of measurement.
Now, recall before we took a look at a simple line
and found that that line was three and a quarter inches long from point A
to point B. We asked, if we didn't have measurements how would we characterize it?
Some might say well it's a straight line. Well, my question would become how straight?
Nothing is perfectly straight. How big is the gap? Some might say well it's a long line.
And I say, well what constitutes long?
That changes greatly from person to person, on their idea of what's long and what’s short.
And what’s a medium line?
Well you see, the more that we can move away from this kind of subjectivity
to repeatable verifiable fact. Which is measurement.
In its purest form, is measurement.
The more we can all carry around the same kind of knowledge.
Now, let's take a look at this number.
As a matter of fact let’s truncate the quarter-inch and just look at the number three.
What is this thing, three? That's an interesting, interesting concept.
A number. Matter of fact I’m going to highlight it. What does that number three mean?
Well it's merely a hieroglyph. That's an interesting word hieroglyph.
Another word for that is symbol. It’s just a symbol. It stands
for three independent ones. See, that's a one. That's a single occurrence.
So things in this world, are either present, one, or their absent, zero.
So if I have three things that are present,
then I would say there are one, two, three.
Equals the symbol three. This is an operation that I perform on that.
1, 1, 1 is three. Now, if I added one more 1 to that.
The symbol would now be 4. So again, it’s just a symbol,
that constitutes for a slot. Now, let me explain what I mean by that. Let's suppose,
that we have
four opportunities. Slots if you will. In which some occurrence
would occur. Either there’s something in that slot, or there isn't.
Therefore, the slots can assume one of two conditions,
zero or one, zero or one, zero or one, zero or one.
Now let's suppose for the sake of argument, on the first time through this slot was zero.
This one was one, zero, one.
Then numerically, we recognize that all that added together is equal to
two. Two of the four slots or
50% of the slots had an occurrence. See we’re measuring at this point.
We’re measuring, we’re measuring on the most elemental level, that there is.
And that number two, is simply symbolic of the presence of something,
as contrasted to the non-presence of it. So again, it’s just a symbol.
That number two, or the number three, or the number four,
or the number five, six, seven, and on and on and on, doesn't care.
It doesn't care where it come from. It doesn't care whether it's the simple
measurement of a line.
Whether it's the radio frequency of an electrical device.
Whether it's the speed of an automobile, or whether it's the service
provided to you by a landscaper. Now, it doesn't really care.
That number two could have been the number of times, he or she mowed your yard.
It could be the number of flowers that they picked from your garden.
It could be the miles per gallon in your automobile.
It could be the number of miles that your radio transmits.
It could be the length of a line.
That number once you get it. It doesn't really care.
And you see, when we do statistics on those numbers.
We just simply have a collection of numbers. Here's some numbers.
The number two, the number three, the number four, and so on. That's what these X’s are.
These are just numbers of things. They don't really care. Statistics don’t care.
It just simply goes in here and crunches that numbers.
Cause we got to remember something. Got to remember a word called torture.
Data in raw form is not information. It's just numbers.
You apply statistics to numbers, to torture it,
to get it to confess what it knows. See statistics is like a torture tool.
It just tortures data until it confesses what it knows.
So, statistics is a way to take those abstract numbers and synthesize them
down to tables, charts,
and summary numbers.
That helps to describe some object, situation, or phenomenon.
That's really what the numbers do and those numbers come from standard scales,
like a ruler. That we put on things to judge
extent, volume,
magnitude, etc. The magnitude is something. The volume is something.
Or the extent to which something occurs. That's what we use these numbers for.
Is to describe that. And then we statistics to operate on those numbers, to torture it
to provide us the tables that tells us ultimately what we want to know.
That's really the power of measurement.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.